Atharva Niranjan Joshi

<u>atharvanj@gmail.com</u> | +44 – 07587039921 | 20 Sark Walk, London, United Kingdom E163PS | <u>linkedin.com/in/atharvanj</u> | <u>atharvanjoshi.github.io/</u>

SUMMARY

I am a passionate Forensic Data Analyst working at KPMG UK specifically in the Unstructured Analytics department. I use Data and Machine Learning for Trader Surveillance. I have completed my MSc. in Data Science from OMUL. I also worked as an AI Intern at CHRE using Computer Vision to improve Oral Cancer diagnosis.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Forensic Data Analyst, KPMG, UK

Oct 2022 - Present

- Actively involved in developing NLP TF IDF Machine Learning model using SGD classifier for text and audio communications to detect Financial and Non-Financial Misconduct in communications.
- Experienced in using Generative AI for synthetic data generation to create Proof of Concept models.
- Experienced in working in an Agile Team of developers focused on requirements scoping and deployment schedules.
- Used Python extensively for data preprocessing such as audio conversion from raw to usable format, speech/voice to text transcription, extracting useful data from noise, deduplication, language translation and logging.
- Experienced in MLOps and involved in creating, deploying, operationalizing and maintaining an end to end automated CI/CD ETL data pipeline with all stages of preprocessing, model deployment and prediction, and ingestion into Relativity platform with little to no manual intervention.
- Used Microsoft Excel for statistical analysis of data as well as creating appropriate dashboards and reports of model performance and monitoring data.
- Experienced in using Azure Cloud Platform to host machine learning models and language transcription containers on dockers, using Rest APIs for various services, storage explorer for receiving data.
- Used SQL extensively for data storage, management and information retrieval to cater to client requests as well as creating appropriate Stored Procedures to be embedded into Python ecosystem.
- Awarded 'Employee of the month' award.

AI Consultant, Centre for Health Research and Education, UK

Jun 2021 - Aug 2022

- Researched and applied various Image object detection and classification models like YOLO v4 and R -CNN using Python and Deep Learning frameworks like PyTorch on existing as well as newly created data.
- Coordinated with various medical institutions for obtaining data, managing and storing on Amazon Web Services (AWS) S3 buckets cloud platform for oral cancer research connecting that with a standalone version of LabelImg for annotation.
- Coordinated with medical experts to understand the domain and in creating appropriate datasets.

Systems Engineer, Infosys Limited, India

Sep 2018 – Sep 2020

- Developed applications in Android and iOS using Xamarin. Forms framework based on C# (Object Oriented Programming) and XAML using DevOps on Microsoft Visual Studio.
- Used Azure Active Directory for authentication and Azure APIs for data retrieval and storage.
- Played an important role in the development cycle by implementing complex features, coordinating with my teammates, tracking the progress of each use case development and bug fixes through the Azure DevOps
 Portal
- Developed Pilot projects and also presented Proof of Concepts, the working of apps through emulator and walkthrough of codes to the clients through Microsoft Teams.
- Nominated and awarded with a Certificate of Appreciation for my performance in the company.

Data Science: Python (Pandas, NumPy, Scikit Learn, TensorFlow), C#, SQL, Excel, Relativity, Azure **Languages**: English (Fluent, C1(IELTS)), Marathi (Fluent, Mother Tongue), Hindi (Intermediate)

EDUCATION

Master of Science (MSc.), Big Data Science with Industrial Experience

Queen Mary University of London

Sep 2020 – Sep 2022

Percentage: 86.31 (Distinction)

Post Graduate Diploma, Data Science Apr 2019 – Feb 2021

IMS ProSchool, India Grade: A

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Information Technology
Savitribai Phule Pune University

Jul 2014 – Jul 2018
Percentage: 63.61 (2:1)

12th (Equivalent to A – Level), Computer Science Feb 2013 – Feb 2014

Maharashtra State Board, India

Percentage: 71.69

10th (Equivalent to GCSE)

Mar 2011 – Mar 2012

Maharashtra State Board, India

Percentage: 84.55

CERTIFICATIONS

- Infosys Certified Python Programmer and Python Associate
- Natural Language Processing with Classification and Vector Spaces Coursera
- Generative AI with Large Language Models Coursera